6221 Crestivew Cir, Stockton CA 95219 david@prothero.com

+1 209 986 4420 http://www.prothero.com/

OVERVIEW

I'm a senior software architect and full-stack developer who is passionate about technology. With over 25 years of experience building solutions and leading technical teams, I've been repeatedly entrusted with building and maintaining high-traffic, public facing web sites and applications.

EXPERTISE

System Architecture
Software Development
Operating at Scale
Cloud Architecture
Educating Developers

EXPERIENCE

TWILIO, San Francisco, CA

2016 - Present

Sr. Engineering Manager (2020 - Present)

- Lead the team of engineers responsible for the **twilio.com** Web site.
- Responsible for the mentoring and career growth of 7 full-time engineers.
- Also responsible for an elastic workforce of 8-10 temporary worker software engineers.
- Work with product and design to help chart the roadmap for the entire web team and ensure adequate resourcing for each program.

Developer Educator (2016 - 2020)

- Lead **developer** and **architect** for the <u>twilio.com/docs</u> platform, built with **Python**, **Django**, **PostgreSQL** and an open source content management system called **Wagtail**.
- **Inspire** and **equip** thousands of developers by authoring and curating technical documentation for Twilio's API's.
- Build and oversee development of a system that generates **thousands of code samples** for the Twilio API's in 7 different languages.
- Using **Vue.js**, help to build <u>TwilioQuest</u>, an RPG-inspired, gamified training experience for developers to learn Twilio.
- Work closely with other Twilio R&D teams to ensure a magical developer experience for Twilio customers.

CALIFORNIA EARTHQUAKE AUTHORITY, Sacramento, CA

2014 - 2016

Application Architect, Web & Cloud

- Lead **developer** and **architect** for <u>Earthquake Brace+Bolt</u>, an ASP.NETMVC, Web API, **AngularJS**, and Bootstrap responsive web application with **RavenDB** backend and hosted in **Azure**.
- Leveraged the platform built for Earthquake Brace+Bolt to begin transitioning the <u>California</u> Earthquake Authority public website from SharePoint to an **Azure** based, responsive platform.
- Designed and built an earthquake insurance premium calculator app for mobile devices using AngularJS, Socket.io, **Node.js**, and WCF web services hosted via **Azure API Management**.
- Created an ASP.NET based documentation website like Github Wikis that utilizes TFS for the backend storage of MarkDown documentation.
- Built full **automation** for Azure resource provisioning, **continuous integration**, and deployment.

6221 Crestivew Cir, Stockton CA 95219 david@prothero.com

+1 209 986 4420

http://www.prothero.com/

LOOSELYCOUPLEDLABS.COM, Stockton, CA

2014 - 2016

Blogger

Wrote a technical blog devoted to software system architecture.

THERAPEUTIC RESEARCH CENTER (TRC), Stockton, CA

2000 - 2014

Director of Software Engineering and IT

- Built ASP.NET, Android, and iOS software solutions and platforms to host TRC's products which bring in over \$20M in revenue annually and see over 25,000 daily visitors.
- Directed a staff of 3 managers who oversaw 6 developers, 3 QA engineers, and 3 dev-ops engineers.
- Made all **technology decisions** for TRC, managing a **\$2M** annual budget.
- Held role of chief architect for both customer facing products and enterprise IT systems, responsible for the availability, security, and safety of over 12TB of valuable business data.
- Performed technical diligence for an 8-figure acquisition, reviewing the target company's technology stack and making recommendations to the acquisition team for potential integration options.
- Led content integration project with WebMD to integrate over 1,000 natural medicines monographs into WebMD's web sites.

PROTHERO CONSULTING, Stockton, CA

1999 - 2000

President and Lead Developer

- Provided **software development consulting** services to a variety of clients.
- Managed all aspects of the small business from accounting to seeking out new clients.
- Stabilized a Delphi application for the California Department of Forestry where the original programmer was no longer available.
- Designed and implemented an ASP-based query system for running reports from an **Oracle** database for a NASA project sub-contracted to Battelle.

ARGOS SOFTWARE, Fresno, CA

1997 - 2000

Research and Development Manager

- Designed architecture for ABECAS Insight, a completely new, Windows-based, client/server ERP system built with Delphi and SQL Server.
- **Trained** over a dozen developers on developing within the new architecture.

CASCADE DATA SOLUTIONS, Albany, OR

1995 - 1997

Programmer/Analyst

EDUCATION

Educational Coursework in Computer Science, 1994

Western Washington University, Bellingham, WA

AA in Business Administration, 1993

Centralia Community College, Centralia, WA